Franky, hold on.
For what?
For your pants, you silly boy. I swear,
you'd think after all that attention you
got last time you went
out dressed like that,
you'd be wise enough not to do it again.
Jeez, I'm just going
out to get a few things.
Now that you're dressed,
you can skeedaddle.
Thanks.
Can't believe she's making
a big dinner just because
the stupid judge is finally
saying Tom's not guilty.
Never was in the first place.
All right.
Rise and shine!
Tom! Iceberg! Get up!
Today's judgment day.
Don't want to sleep
through your big trial.
Let's get down to the harbor.
They're gonna hand down Tom's sentence.
The spectators are boarding
the ship in droves.
The people are really interested.
Seems like it'll be a big trial.
Have you had a chance to see
the Sea Train yet, Your Honor?
I have indeed. Quite impressive.
A true feat of ingenuity.
He fulfilled his end of the bargain.
I'm certain the people will
rejoice to see their hero go free.
Is Tom here yet?
I wish I could start already.
Come on, we've got to hurry
before all the seats are taken.
I know, I can't wait to see the look on
his face when the judge lets him off.
What a trip.
Wow, can't believe it's been 14 years.
The ship's under attack!
Get away from it! Hooray! What the?
Is this a pirate raid?
But now, where is this attack even
coming from? Hey, look! Over there!
What?
Some kind of fleet!
Those look like battleships!
Those pirates are attacking us!
There's so many of them, are
they all working together?
Everybody run!
Get out of the harbor! Hurry!
It's not safe, they're the
water! Look out! Look out!
What's happening?
What the hell?
Who's doing this?
Who took my ships?
Tom, we're in trouble.
Frankie's ships are attacking the harbor.
It's not him, I saw him earlier.
He wouldn't do such a thing.
I know that.
Look, I'm positive it's
not Franky doing it.
This is a whole other
kind of trouble we're in.
Let's put a stop to it. Right.
Pirates, or worse, the government.
That's right!
Hurry! Into the city!
Get away from the harbor!
They're still inside!
Bastards!
They're gonna pay!
Who the hell is it? Huh?
Who the hell is screwing
around with my ships?
Please come with us, your honor!
The ship can't take much more!
Who does that fleet belong to?
The raid on the judicial ship
was a success, sir. Excellent.
Now I want you to proceed
to step two immediately.
We must ensure that justice
is served. Yes, sir.
Now, let's begin your impending
trial in earnest, shall we, Tom?
It looks like it's about to go down.
All right, let's get back
to Scrappy Violet. Right.
Hey, the fleet is starting
to turn around. Hold on.
I'm pretty sure I've seen
those ships somewhere before.
Tom, look.
They're heading this way.
They're getting closer.
I think that we can catch them.
I can't imagine what the hell they were
thinking I can't get
pulling a stunt like that.
I see two men approaching from the island.
That's Tom.
Right, let's abandon this ship.
What the?
Not a soul on this thing. Same here.
I don't see anybody.
What the hell is going on here?
More of Frankie's ships
Damn
it
my
battle Frankies they're destroyed?
Tom, the iceberg.
Hey, can you hear me?
Are you okay?
What in the hell happened here?
Tell me what's going on.
Hey, I -
You stupid ass.
It's your fault this happened.
It was that intelligence agent.
He used your damn battleships
to attack people at the harbor.
No, I didn't hurt anybody.
I told you this would
happen, but you don't listen.
Listen, Franky.
If you killed a Sea King with this
ship, then it's a dangerous weapon.
You're making it easier for somebody
who wants to use it like one, you idiot.
My ships did this.
They hurt Tom.
Look.
We have the ability to create
powerful things. Weapons.
Even if you weren't trying to.
Weapons are made to hurt people.
Whether you want them to or
not, they can hurt your friends.
That's what the government did to us.
They used your creations
to hurt a lot of people.
People we care about.
And now they're going
to put the blame on us.
They want to back Tom into a corner
so they can get those blueprints.
After all this, you still think
your hands don't have blood on them?
If Tom gets taken away, if he
hangs for this, I swear on my life.
I will never forgive you!
Never, you under - Stop it!
Tom.
It's not his fault.
Don't blame him.
He didn't do this.
You still believe that after
everything that happened?
Oh no.
This is one of the
special harpoons I made.
Once it pierces its target,
you can't pull it out.
I'm so sorry.
Don't apologize.
It's barely even a scratch.
Over there!
We found them!
Tom's been injured!
Wait, why is he hurt?
Weren't they the ones behind the attack?
It doesn't make any sense!
The townspeople, they're here.
Now then?
I believe this is the part.
where you come along quietly.
Damn you, Spanda!
Spandam, you fool.
Now let's get going, you criminals.
These are the culprits
behind the attack rest easy
everyone we the men of CP5
have Destroyed their attack
ships they'll cause no
more trouble I'm sure the
judge Would have acquitted
him of those old charges
today if so then why did
he do Something like that
he was friends with the
king of the pirates who
knows what He's capable of
pleased to meet you your
honor my name is Spandam I'm
with CP5 A pleasure, and thanks.
You saved us.
We can take over the investigation
from here if you don't mind.
We'll give them a full interrogation.
Just try talking your way out of this one.
The trust they had in
you has been shattered.
Soon those blueprints for the
ancient weapons will be mine.
How could this happen?
First off, about the Sea Train.
Magnificent work.
With its help, Water 7 will
continue to grow and flourish.
For that, on the previous charge
of building Gold Rogers' ship!
Your acquittal today had pretty
much already been decided?
Knowing that,
why in the world would you commit such
heinous crime and erase that opportunity?
Please, explain yourself That's a lie!
It wasn't Tom or any of us that attacked
the judicial ship It
was that idiot Spandam!
He's the one responsible!
Sure it was.
He's not serious, is he?
What kind of crap is he trying to pull?
Why would a government agency
like CP5 attack a judicial ship?
There's no way!
You're gonna have to come up
with a better lie than that, Mr.
Apprentice.
Your name is Cutty Flam, correct?
I believe that was the name we
took down from you when we caught
you red-handed on board one of
those treacherous raid ships.
And correct me if I'm mistaken,
but weren't those very same raid
ships all made by your company?
Ships that would do such a horrible thing.
Something so awful are no longer my ships!
Tom tore off his chains!
He's on a rampage! Take aim!
He just hit him.
Tom has never hit Franky before.
What'd you do that for?
They're no longer your ships, huh?
Don't you ever say that again!
What's wrong with saying that?
I wish I'd never made them!
If those ships didn't exist then
nobody would have gotten hurt.
When a ship is built.
No matter what type.
It's neither good nor evil.
I don't care what kind of ship you
choose to make for the rest of your life.
Remember.
Even if the ships you build hurt someone.
Even if they destroy the world.
Even if no one else does.
Their creator must love
them unconditionally.
The one who made them
must never deny them!
Don't place the blame on the ships!
You must be proud of every
ship you've ever created!
Iceberg, Franky, whatever happens,
don't interfere with what I'm
about to do, no matter what.
It's the world government
who pinned this crime on us,
and it's the world government
who will be the ones to judge it.
There's no way for us to be
cleared of these charges.
It's over.
It must be tough for
you to see your innocent
ships being used for
something as horrible as this.
I bet you really want to hit
that guy, don't you, Franky?
What are you doing?
He's going crazy again.
What is he doing? Stop it, please.
You're making things worse
than they already are.
Can you even comprehend the pain
that you put that boy through?
Fire!
They shot him.
Tom, no!
Tranquilizers, huh?
Not so tough now, are you?
Sir, is you right, fish man?
Tom, wait.
Why are you doing this?
What are you standing around for?
Get over there and apprehend them!
We're going to take Tom and every last one
of his villainous workers
down to Eni's lobby.
Who would have thought that Tom
could be such a dangerous guy?
What the hell was he thinking?
Just what you'd expect from a
man who sold his soul to pirates.
He made those battleships and waited
around for a chance like this to use them.
How dare you talk about him
like that, you bastards!
Stop it!
It's all right.
Tom!
I'd like to confess. Hmm?
The raid on the judicial
ship was led by me.
That's not true!
Why would you say that?
But I have a request.
Save your breath, fish man!
Nobody gives a damn about your...
Shut your mouth, CP5!
So, what is this request?
If building the C-Train was supposed to be
considered a pardon for
one charge against me,
then I'd like to be pardoned
for today's charges. Huh?
Even if that request is granted,
you'll be right back to
where you were to begin with.
With a charge of building a ship
for the King of the Pirates,
which will result in the maximum penalty.
Sounds good.
I like that better anyway.
Giving a hand to that Roger guy
is something I'll never forget.
In fact, it's something
I take great pride in.
He's proud of that?
I can't believe he'd make such a bold
claim about something so despicable.
Traitor!
Fishman!
You regret that! Why, Tom?
Tell me!
It's for the best.
Now, listen.
Don't blame yourself for this.
I never thought the world government would
go to such extremes to get the blueprints.
And the situation with Roger
only makes the matter worse.
Even so, it doesn't have to be this way!
No, it's fine.
Look around you.
Even if I'm charged with
a crime from 14 years ago,
nothing else about this town is
the same now as it was back then.
This island is alive and strong.
This is only the beginning.
No matter what ends up happening to me,
I was still able to help this town.
My dream has finally begun to run.
Tom, don't please!
Tom, no!
Iceberg, Franky, take
care of the blueprints.
Kokoro, Yokozuna, thank
you for everything.
The tranquilizers finally kicked in!
Capture those three for
the judicial ship attack!
Yes, sir!
Hold it.
I'm amending the charges for the crime of
designing and building a ship for gold.
Roger.
The king of the pirates.
Tom and Tom alone will be apprehended
and taken to Annie's Lobby.
That is all.
What in the hell got into
that old geezer's head?
Whatever.
I don't need his lackeys.
Release those two. apprentices.
Tom can't be saved from this.
It's the government we're up against.
There's nothing we can do. Endure it.
Tom traded his life for yours.
If you make them your enemy, you won't be
able to win, no matter how many lives you?
have to give.
Annie's lobby is the government's
personal judicial island.
Not one single person who's been
sent to that dreadful place has ever
been seen again the C train is
ready for departure sir we can leave
anytime you like very good let's
get moving men load up the prisoner
I can't this bloated fish man is
He's going for a little train ride.
Endure this!
Stop it!
Really messed up his face.
Trump's apprentice is
the one on a rampage.
No, stop!
Let her get him!
Capture that criminal!
The rest of you, take Tom to the train!
That's not gonna happen!
Nobody's taking him anywhere!
Fire at will!
I'm staying right here!
Are you okay?
After him!
Hurry!
Get out of here!
Fire!
Damn it!
He got away!
I'll get that Cutty Flam brat
if it's the last thing I do!
That little criminal will
pay for what he's done!
Mark my words, once this case is over,
I'll have him sent to the gallows!
Spandam, he's here!
What?
Now!
It's...
it's Cutty Flam, sir! What? Where?
Standing out on the tracks ahead of us,
and it appears that he's
holding some sort of weapon!
Stay right there, Yokozuna.
He's out of his mind!
What should we do, sir?
Are you out of your mind, too?
We keep on going.
That's what he wants us to do, right?
Don't worry about him. Right. Yes, sir.
All right, Puffing Top, that's far enough.
What do you think you're doing?
Where are you taking your creator?
I won't let you pass.
Give me Tom back!
You hear me?
Stop now, Katorea!
I see, so your parents
just abandoned you, huh?
That's terrible.
Hey, stop laughing at me! Fine, then.
Come stay with me.
Tom, I don't want to build ships anymore.
I can't love ships that hurt
the people I care so much about.
I won't do it.
And even so, my goal in
life is to be just like you.
Come back.
Come back and teach me once again.
Because someday, I want to
build my own dream ship.
A ship that will proudly
sail bravely over uncharted
waters all the way to
the ends of the world.